

Toronto, Canada Permanent Resident in Canada

GitHub | LinkedIn | Google Scholar duckhai.le@mail.utoronto.ca | (+1) 437 249 2462

Research Statement

I'm an AI researcher with a business mindset. My research is not limited to a single topic but rather spans most aspects of AI, e.g. speech recognition, natural language processing, computer vision, time-series analysis, large language models, multi-modality, data-centric AI, and semi-supervised learning. Most of my works focused on bringing theoretical AI to real-world applications that serve business needs. Hire me and get 21 AI researchers.

Education

University of Toronto

Toronto, Canada

Master of Applied Science in Biomedical Engineering, fully-funded program

January 2024 - Present

- $\bullet\,$ The university was ranked 1st in Canada, 9th in the world in AI (QS Rankings)
- Research area: Machine Learning for Multivariate Time-series
- Supervisor: Prof. Shehroz Khan (h-index 26)

RWTH Aachen University

Aachen, Germany

December 2022

Bachelor Thesis in Computer Science

- The university was ranked 2nd in Germany and 50th in the world in Computer Science (THE Rankings)
- Thesis supervisor: Prof. Hermann Ney (h-index 113), Prof. Ralf Schlüter (h-index 50)
- Thesis title: Unsupervised Pre-Training for Vietnamese Automatic Speech Recognition in the HYKIST Project [DOI]
- Thesis grade: 1.0/6.0 (German grade), 100/100 (International percentage)

FH Aachen University of Applied Sciences

Jülich, Germany

Bachelor in Biomedical Engineering, taught-in-German program

December 2022

- The university was ranked 1st among Universities of Applied Sciences in Germany in Engineering and Informatics (WiWo Ranking)
- Thesis supervisor: Prof. Ilya Digel (h-index 23)
- Overall grade: 2.2/6.0 (German grade), 80/100 (International percentage)

Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Bachelor in International Economic Relations

October 2016

- The university was ranked 1st overall in Vietnam and 701-750th in the world (QS Rankings)
- Top 100 out of 354897 candidates (0.02%) with total scores of 27/30 in the Vietnamese National High School Graduation Examination 2015 in Mathematics, Physics and English
- Grade: 1st ranked Valedictorian

Industry Experience

FPT Software AI Center, FPT Corporation

Remote

AI Researcher

March 2024 - Present

- · Leader of 20 AI residents, engineers and PhD students
- Research project: Research and Product Development of Multimodal Multilingual Large Language Models

Research Experience

University Health Network

Toronto, Canada

Graduate Research Assistant

January 2024 - Present

- University Health Network is ranked as the world's 5th best hospital (Newsweek 2023) and ranked 1st in rehabilitation.
- Research project: Predicting Agitation in People Living with Dementia

Machine Learning and Human Language Technology Group, RWTH Aachen University

Aachen, Germany

Student Research Assistant

May 2021 - Present

- Research supervisor: **Prof. Hermann Ney** (h-index 113, 63000+ citations, the most cited researcher and the highest h-index in the world in Speech Recognition and in Machine Translation)
- Research co-supervisor: **Prof. Ralf Schlüter** (h-index 50, 12000+ citations)
- Research topic: Semi-Supervised Learning for Medical Domain Speech Recognition

FH Aachen University of Applied Sciences

Geilenkirchen, Germany

Research Intern

January 2016 - March 2016

- Research labs: Freshman Laboratory of Electrical Engineering, Laboratory of Molecular Medicine and Cell, Biophysics Lab, Chemistry Laboratory, and Freshman Biomedical Labor
- · Received certificates for contribution

Awards & Honors

SGS Research Travel Grant	2024
University of Toronto (950 CAD for LREC-COLING 2024 - the highest amount ever) ORT Conference Participation Award	2024
University Health Network (500 CAD for LREC-COLING 2024)	2024
Top 12 HackerRank in Germany	2020
HackerRank - the largest competitive programming platform in the world	
Valedictorian Scholarship of Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City	2015

Selected Open-Source Projects

Demo for Multilingual Speech Translation

- The first free-of-charge medical speech translation API in the world, being deployed on cloud in German medical centers to support
 conversations between German doctors and international patients without language barriers
- Co-contributor of the demo

Awesome Competitive Programming Problems

- · Curated extensive library of Python data structures and algorithms specifically designed for competitive programming contests
- Solved various problems including String Manipulation, Graph Theory, Greedy, Dynamic Programming, Sliding Window, Mathematics and Recursion
- On GitHub top 1 trending, received 170+ stars

Non-Technical Experience

Mathnasium October 2023 – November 2023

Instructor - Part time Toronto, Canada

- Communicated with students in an understandable way about daily lessons
- Developed automated teaching tools and methods to help students learn mathematics

Techniker Krankenkasse

March 2016 – June 2016

Volunteer - Full time

Geilenkirchen, Germany

- The company is Germany's largest health insurance fund
 - Maintained business contacts with 1000+ student customers, organized and executed 3 events to advertise company's insurance packages, and created marketing concepts
 - · Received certificate for contribution

Technical Skills

Programming skills:

- Programming Languages: Python, MATLAB, Java (basic)
- Databases (basic): Snowflake, SQL, MongoDB
- Deep Learning Frameworks: Keras, Tensorflow, Pytorch, Fairseq, HuggingFace
- Data Science Libraries: NumPy, SciKit-Learn, Pandas, SciPy, Seaborn, Matplotlib
- Data Analysis and Statistical Tools (basic): SPSS, Excel
- Image Processing Libraries: OpenCV, scikit-image
- Operating Systems: Linux, Git
- · Document Preparation: LaTeX, Markdown

<u>Relevant courseworks</u>: Medical Statistics, Information Processing, Image Processing, Medical Computer Science, Introducing MATLAB, Introducing to Python.

Spoken languages: Vietnamese (Native), English (IELTS 7.0), German (C1)

List of co-authors I actively engage with

- Mentee:
 - 1. Khai-Nguyen Nguyen (11.2023 Present): PhD student at College of William & Mary, research intern at FPT Corporation
 - 2. Long Vo (11.2023 Present): Bachelor student at University of Cincinnati
 - 3. Ryan Zhang (02.2024 06.2024): Undergraduate thesis student at University of Toronto, now at Johns Hopkins University
- Peer Collaborators:
 - 1. Trang Nguyen: PhD student at Stanford University
 - 2. Jerry Ngo: Researcher at MIT CSAIL
 - 3. Ngo Ba Hung: Postdoc Fellow at Chonnam National University
- Senior Collaborators:
 - 1. Truong Son Hy: Professor at Indiana State University, AI Scientist at FPT Corporation
 - 2. Anh Totti Nguyen: Professor at Auburn University, h-index 21, 11000+ citations

Publications

All publications are peer-reviewed/submitted at top-tier venues in AI

(*) Equal contribution

Work to be submitted: Preprints are available in Overleaf

12. Predicting Agitation with Motion Sensors placed in the Homes of People living with Dementia

Khai Le-Duc, Ali Abedi, Charlene Chu, Shehroz S. Khan

To be submitted to Gerontology Journal, Special Issue: AI-Driven Measurement in Gerontological Research

11. MultiMed: Multilingual Medical Speech Recognition via Attention Encoder Decoder

Khai Le-Duc, Phuc Phan, Tan-Hanh Pham Truong-Son Hy

To be submitted to EMNLP Industry track 2024

10. wav2graph: A Framework for Supervised Learning Knowledge Graph from Speech

Khai Le-Duc*, Quy Anh Dang*, Oanh Tran, Tan-Hanh Pham Truong-Son Hy

To be submitted to EMNLP Industry track 2024

9. Speech Sentiment Reasoning for Healthcare

Khai Le-Duc*, Khai-Nguyen Nguyen*, Bach Phan Tat, Duy Le, Jerry Ngo, Long Vo-Dang, Anh Totti Nguyen, Truong-Son Hy

To be submitted to EMNLP Industry track 2024

8. Large Vision-Language Model for Joint Chest X-ray Localization and Classification Task

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>*, Ryan Zhang*, Ngoc Son Nguyen*, Tan-Hanh Pham, Anh Dao, Ba Hung Ngo, Anh Totti Nguyen, Truong-Son Hy

To be submitted to EMNLP Industry track 2024

Under anonymized period: Preprints are privately available in GitHub repo

7. A Wearable Device Dataset for Mental Health Assessment Using Laser Doppler Flowmetry and Fluorescence Spectroscopy Sensors

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>*, Tan-Hanh Pham*, Minh Ngoc Nguyen*, Trang Nguyen, Quang Minh Luu, Ba Kien Tran, Truong-Son Hy, Viktor Dremin, Sergei Sokolovsky, Edik Rafailov

Triple-blind period, submitted to ICDM 2024, 63 pages

6. Domain-Shift in Medical Machine Translation

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>, Hung-Phong Tran, Long Vo-Dang, Khai-Nguyen Nguyen, Truong-Son Hy, Shehroz Khan Triple-blind period, submitted to ICDM 2024

5. Dynamic Intermediate Loss for Fine-tuning Self-Supervised Models

Khai Le-Duc, Christoph Lüscher, Ralf Schlüter

Triple-blind period, submitted to ICDM 2024

Preprint

4. Medical Spoken Named Entity Recognition

Khai Le-Duc, David Thulke, Hung-Phong Tran, Long Vo-Dang, Ralf Schlüter Overall 3-3-3-3/5 at ACL 2024 (A*-ranked conference), 40 pages

Peer-reviewed

3. Real-time Speech Summarization for Medical Conversations

<u>Khai Le-Duc</u>*, Khai-Nguyen Nguyen*, Long Vo-Dang, Truong-Son Hy Interspeech 2024 (A-ranked Conference by CORE, #1 Conference in Speech Processing)

2. VietMed: A Dataset and Benchmark for Automatic Speech Recognition of Vietnamese in the Medical Domain Khai Le-Duc

LREC-COLING 2024 (A-ranked Joint Conference by CORE, acceptance rate 52%), 27 pages

1. Development of Hybrid ASR Systems for Low Resource Medical Domain Conversational Telephone Speech Christoph Lüscher, Mohammad Zeineldeen, Zijian Yang, Peter Vieting, <u>Khai Le-Duc</u>, Weiyue Wang, Ralf Schlüter, Hermann Ney

ITG Speech Communication 2023 (#5 ASR Conference by Research.com)